MIHAI CIOBOTARU



Computer Science Student Facultatea de Informatica, 3rd year Universitatea Alexandru Ioan Cuza Iasi

CONTACT

contact@mihaiciobotaru.com

+40 774450052

www.mihaiciobotaru.com

9

@mihaiciobotaru

Ciobotaru Mihai

SKILLS

Programming

C/C++ Java

PLSQL PHP

HTML/CSS

TailwindCSS

Javascript

Python

Operating Systems

Windows

Linux

Languages

English



GENERAL SKILLS

Stress resistant Hardworking

Fastlearner Sociale and frendly

Good time management

Desire to learn **Patience**

Openness to criticism

Problem-solving **Teamwork**

FAVORITE QUOTE

A good code is like a story, not a puzzle.

ABOUT ME

I'm a student who looks forward to learning more about computer science. I like most artificial intelligence, web and game development but I'm passionate about all coding in general. Besides software development I'm also curious to learn about arduino and microcontrollers. For more details about me and my projects you can visit my personal github or my personal website. Besides the projects presented there I have experience with programming languages and algorithms from the university and not only. My general interest is artifcial intelligence and I'm following a Harvard course on this subject.

WORK HISTORY

(1) 09/2022 - 09/20222

Siena Marketing Website - freelance project

6 06/2021 - 06/2021

Towing Website- freelance project

EDUCATION

10/2020 - present

Universitatea Alexandru Ioan Cuza Iasi, Facultatea de Informatica

1 09/2016 - 06/2020

Liceul Economic Mihail Kogalniceanu, Focsani

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Electron

The project aimed to be accomplished is called "Electron". This project consists of a graphical interface that gives the client the possibility to create, modify, save and load electronical circuits. Also the application has a theme and language menu and a hidden snake game. I have learned about SFML and C with the help of this project.

Genetic Algorithms problems

I've solved problems related to Genetic Algorithms made during the second year of University. Genetic Algorithms have been one of my favorite subjects. Each solution to a problem has a documentation of what I have made. Shortly, I have learned about heuristic search algorithms (SAHC, NAHC, SA) and genetic algorithms. I have used them to solve multi-modal functions. In one such project, I've created an algorithm that aims to solve Travelling Salesman Problem using genetic algorithms in C++.

Cryptography algorithms

I've implemented cryptograppic algorithms from scratch as a part of my learning proccess. Some of the algorithms are DES, RSA CRT and SHA.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Personal Website

My personal website can be found on a google search of my name or following www.mihaiciobotaru.com link. I've created this website as a presentation of my skills and to post computer science articles. I've created the website using HTML, Javascript, ThreeJS and Tailwind CSS and also blender for the 3D Objects.

Siena Marketing Website

This website was created for a marketing agency as their bussiness website. In order to create this website I've started from an envato website template and modified it. Languages I've used were CSS, Javascript and HTML. The website can be viewed on www.sienamarketing.ro.

Stamp Worldn't

The product is intended for people that share the passion of filatelic products. The aim for the user is to search, create, add or share albums of filatelic products and to receive statistics and generated data about ranks and tops about the data and about other users. This product is presented as a new product, autonomous, but still similar to sites that share the same field. It shares the same ideas with many other sites such as Stamp World.

Towing website

This website has been done for a local towing company in Focsani, Romania. The website is still live on the web under the domain tractarifocsaninonstop.ro but I do not own it anymore and the website needs fixes for responsiveness and to be added a gallery page. I've learned about frontend, design trends such as glassmorphism and neumorphism and web development with the help of this project. The project was not continued due to disagreements with the client. In order to code this, I have used HTML, CSS and Javascript.

Arduino display distance on LCD

I made this code in my learning process of Arduino. For this code I have used as hardware: $1 \times LCD1602 \text{ module}$, $1 \times RGB \text{ LED}$, $3 \times 220 \text{ ohm resistors}$, $21 \times MM \text{ mires}$, $1 \times HC\text{-SR04}$, $4 \times F\text{-M}$ wires; and as software I have used LiquidCrystal and HCSR04 libraries. The code measures the distance using the ultrasonic sensor module and displays it on the LCD1602 module. If there are less than 25 cm the led will light red, if there are less than 70 cm- blue and else it will light green.

Wheater website

This app provides a weather web which lets the user insert a country or a city's name to learn what's the weather there in that moment. I used this repo to learn more about api's and how they work. I have used HTML, CSS and Javascript for this project.